

Profile

Skilled Machinery Engineer and Administrative Assistant currently pursuing a role as a Frontend Developer where I can design and develop web apps that impacts the user experience. I am a quick learner with good communication skills. I can also efficiently work under pressure and am a good team player.

Professional Experience

Frontend Engineer, *Joyce Infratech Pvt Ltd*

01/2023 - 03/2023

Designed and developed websites using HTML, JavaScript and CSS technologies.

Chennai, India

• Created accessible and maintainable user interface.

• Managing software workflow.

Administration, Joyce Infratech Pvt Ltd

08/2022 - 12/2022

• Employee management- Assigning roles and responsibilities, accounting.

Chennai, India

- Client management
- Financial management
- · Reports generation

Plants and Machinery Engineer, Larsen and Toubro

07/2022 - 09/2022

Banglore, India

- Monitoring and Inspecting over 150 machines and Vehicles.
- Maintenance for the following equipment- Excavator, Diesel generators, Road cutting machine, Backhoe loader, Pickup Van, Tipper, and Roller.
- Overseeing and allocating machines for the respective sites.
- · Report generation.

Education

B.E. Mechanical Engineering,

06/2018 - 05/2022

Vel Tech Multi Tech Dr. Rangarajan & Dr. Sakunthala Engineering College **CGPA 7.9**

Avadi, Chennai, India

Higher Secondary Course, Vijayantha Model Senior Secondary School (State board)

06/2017 - 04/2018

Computer science & Math's Stream 75.75%

Avadi, Chennai, India

Secondary School Examination, Kendriya Vidyalaya H.V.F (CBSE)

03/2015 - 04/2016

CGPA 8.6

Avadi, Chennai, India

Certificates

Internship-ICF Perambur

A two-week internship in ICF (2019)

Internship- Central Institute of Plastics Engineering & Technology (CIPET)

A month internship in the year 2020

Projects

Vehicle Monitoring and Rear end Collision Avoidance using CAN Protocol

11/2021 - 04/2022

Final year Project

Speed Breaker Generating Electric Power

12/2020 - 06/2021

Mini project done during the third year of Engineering

Awards

Best Cultural Secretary, Vel Tech Multi Tech

2022

Appreciation award for organizing the college cultural, 2022.

Skills

Javascript CSS

HTML5 Analytical Skills

Adaptability Time Management

Communication Skill Teamwork

Creativity

Interests

- Cars and technology
- Photography, Videography, Cinematography
- Musical Instruments- Drums, Guitar, Keyboard
- Video Editing and VFX
- Gaming

Languages

• Tamil • English

Hindi

Declaration

I hereby declare that the details and information given above are complete and true to the best of my knowledge.

K Shelton Bilgates

Avadi